SAMUEL L. RANDALL, AI / ML Professional

samrandall@alumni.stanford.edu

With over 7 years of experience in data and software, I help teams use data, software and AI to solve technical and business challenges. I have expertise scraping and organizing data, training and integrating ML models into software. I have strong software engineering skills and can operate on many stacks. I also have experience creating business strategy, through start-up experience.

Education

Stanford University, MS. Computational & Mathematical Engineering DGSAC Exceptional Master's Student Award.

Johns Hopkins University, BS. Applied Math and Public Health. Minor in Computer Science and Environmental Science.

Experience

BlueLightAI, Principal Applied Scientist

January 2023 — Present

- Led business initiatives to develop product market fit; collaborated with executives, product head, VP of engineering, Head of Data Science and principal scientists to launch MVP.
 - Required communication of advanced ML and mathematical concepts to business people.
- Developed software algorithm to automatically identify systemic error patterns in ML models, saving data scientist teams 20% of their time sorting manually through errors.
- Implemented generalized & differentiated software to support team members in their data analyses; resulting in productized software, drastically reducing errors and greatly improving team efficiency.

Athena Security, iOS Engineer

2020 - 2022

- Integration of sensors and ML model into MVP fever detection iOS app in 6 weeks.
- Engaged in rapid feedback loop with prospects & customers to engineer the product to suit needs, making necessary third-party integrations and satisfying new feature requests.

PHICOR, Research Analyst

2017 - 2020

- Scripted the execution & analysis of simulation jobs; automating a previously labor-intensive process.
- Streamlined labor-intensive download / organization process of large (>1500 files) dataset.

Volunteer & Continuing Education

California Search & Rescue, Duty Officer, General Member

2022 — Present

• I receive the call from emergency service, dispatch the team & coordinate logistics.

Climate Change Solution-Oriented Reading Group, Cofounder	Č	2023 — Present
Stanford University, Sighted Running Guide for Visually Impaired Students		2022 - 2023
Large Language Model (LLM) Reading Group, General Member		2023 - 2024

STEM Teaching & Tutoring Experience

Ordinary Differential Equations, Course Assistant	2022
Software Development for Engineers and Scientists, Course Assistant	2021
Juni Learning, Computer Science Tutor for children aged 5-18	2019 - 2020

Skills

Machine Learning, Computer Vision (CV), NLP, scikit-learn, LLMs, Node.js, Python, Java, Javascript, Swift, C/C++, TensorFlow, PyTorch, git, Unix, Deep Learning, Optimization, Explainable AI, CUDA, Data Structures.